Guide to the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III. Office of the Director General
  - Subseries III.1: Subject File.
    - Correspondence, Reading File, Chronological (Box DG/2)
    - April-May 1944 (Box DG/2)
    - June-July 1944 (Box DG/2)
    - August-September 1944 (Box DG/2)
    - October-December 1944 (Box DG/2)
    - December 1-16, 1944 (Box DG/2)
    - December 17-30, 1944 (Box DG/2)
    - January 1945 (Box DG/2)
    - February 1-8, 1945 (Box DG/2)
    - February 9-14, 1945 (Box DG/2)
    - February 15-28, 1945 (Box DG/2)
    - March 1-8, 1945 (Box DG/2)
    - March 9-20, 1945 (Box DG/2)
    - March 21-31, 1945 April 1945 (Box DG/2)
    - May 1945 (Box DG/2)
    - April-May, 1945 (misc.?) (Box DG/2)
    - June 1945 (Box DG/3)
    - July 1945 (Box DG/3)
    - August 1945 (Box DG/3)
    - September 1945 (Box DG/3)
    - October 1945 (Box DG/3)
    - November 1945 (Box DG/3)
    - December 1945 (Box DG/3)
    - January and February 1946 (Box DG/3)
    - March 1946 (Box DG/3)
    - May 1946 (Box DG/3)
    - August-October 1946 (Box DG/3)
    - September 6, 1946-January 27, 1947 (Box DG/3)
    - January-February 1947 (Box DG/3)
    - 27 January-31 December 1947 (Box DG/3)
    - March-May 1947 (Box DG/3)
    - June-September 1947 (Box DG/3)
    - October-December 1947 (Box DG/3)
    - Chronological File, Director General (Box DG/3)
    - January 1947 (Box DG/3)
    - February 1947 (Box DG/3)
    - March 1947 (Box DG/3)
    - April 1947 (Box DG/3)
    - May 1947 (Box DG/3)
    - June 1947 (Box DG/3)
    - July 1947 (Box DG/3)
    - August 1947 (Box DG/3)
    - September 1947 (Box DG/3)
    - October 1947 (Box DG/3)
    - Chronological File, Director General (Box DG/3)
    - November 1947 (Box DG/3)
    - December 1947 (Box DG/3)
    - January 1948 (Box DG/4)
    - January-27 May 1948 (Box DG/4)
    - January-September 1948 (reading file) (Box DG/4)
    - February 1948 (Box DG/4)
    - March 1948 (Box DG/4)
    - May 1948 (Box DG/4)
    - June 1948 (Box DG/4)
    - July-August (October) 1948 (Box DG/4)
    - Chronological Reading File, Correspondence (Box DG/4)
    - January-April 1945 (Box DG/4)
    - April-December 1945 (Box DG/4)
    - January-March 1946 (Box DG/4)
    - April-July 1946 (Box DG/4)
    - Cigarettes - (Ex-S.S. Ripley) (Box DG/4)
    - Closure of Headquarters (Box DG/4)
    - Closure of European Missions, 30 June 1947, Letters to and from Member Governments, Mission Heads and Others (Box DG/4)
    - Closure of European Missions, Letters and Cables to Government Representatives ending June 1947 (Box DG/4)
    - Closure - European Missions (Box DG/4)
    - Closure Plan - European Region (Box DG/4)
    - Closure - Port Offices (Box DG/4)
    - Clothing Collection (keep short time) (Box DG/4)
    - Coal (Box DG/5)
    - Collins, S.J., Personal (Box DG/5)
    - Combined Boards (Box DG/5)
    - Combined Chiefs of Staff (Box DG/5)
    - Committees (Box DG/5)
    - Ability to Pay (Committee 23) (Box DG/5)
    - Audit Subcommittee (Box DG/5)
    - Audit Subcommittee (Box DG/5)
    - Central Committee - Committee on Supplies (Box DG/5)
    - Central Committee - Program Subcommittee (Box DG/5)
    - Central Committee - Procedural Questions (Box DG/5)
    - Combined Food Board - Fats and Oils Committee (Box DG/5)
    - Contributions (Box DG/5)
    - Council for Europe, Committee of the (Box DG/5)
    - Council for the Far East, Committee of the (Box DG/5)
    - Council for the Far East, Committee of the (Box DG/5)
    - Emergency Food Council (Box DG/5)
    - European and Technical Subcommittees (Box DG/5)
    - Personnel Policies (Box DG/5)
    - Reorganization, Special Committee on (Box DG/5)
    - Standing Technical Committees (five), Appointment of Personnel of by Herbert H. Lehman (Box DG/5)
    - Technical Welfare, Committee on (Box DG/5)
    - DG File on Committees (Box DG/5)
    - UNRRA Committees - Members, Alternates (Box DG/5)
    - UNRRA Committees, Use of (Box DG/5)
    - Communications (Box DG/5)
    - Communications - Survey Report, Headquarters (Box DG/5)
    - Conferences (Box DG/5)
    - Accounting Conference, Headquarters, Documents (Box DG/5)
    - Accounting Conferences (Box DG/5)
    - Food Conference (Box DG/5)
    - Governor Lehman's Conference with 25 Editors (Box DG/5)
    - San Francisco Conference (Box DG/5)
    - Supply Conference with Mission Chiefs (Box DG/5)
    - Miscellaneous Conferences (Box DG/5)
    - Congratulations (Box DG/5)
    - Congress (Box DG/5)
    - Contributed Supplies (Box DG/5)
    - Contributions (Box DG/5)
    - Contributions of Member Governments (Box DG/5)
    - Contributions - Miscellaneous (Box DG/5)
    - Controller (Box DG/5)
    - Controller (Box DG/6)
    - Cooperatives (Box DG/6)
    - [Report: Political Trends in Europe of Concern to UNRRA] (Box DG/6)
    - Council Sessions, UNRRA (Box DG/6)
    - Council, UNRRA (Box DG/6)
    - 2nd Session (Box DG/6)
    - 2nd Session (Box DG/6)
    - 2nd Session, General (Box DG/6)
    - 2nd Session, Director General's Report (Box DG/6)
    - 3rd Session (Box DG/6)
    - 3rd Session (Box DG/6)
    - 4th Session (Box DG/6)
    - 4th Session (Box DG/6)
    - 5th Session (Box DG/6)
    - 6th Session (Box DG/6)
    - 7th Session (Box DG/6)
    - Currency, Local (Box DG/6)
    - Currency Proceeds, Local (Box DG/6)
    - "D" (Box DG/6)
    - Decorations and Awards, UNRRA Personnel (Box DG/6)
    - Diplomatic Adviser - Miscellaneous (Box DG/6)
    - Diplomatic Adviser, 1944 (Box DG/6)
    - Diplomatic Immunities (Box DG/6)
    - Director General - Copies of letters and Cables Between Director General and Heads of Governments, Foreign Ministers, etc. (Box DG/6)
    - Albania to India (Box DG/6)
    - Iran to Yugoslavia (Box DG/6)
    - Director General - Trips (Box DG/6)
    - China, October 1947 (Box DG/6)
    - Europe, July-September 1946 (Box DG/6)
    - Europe, March-April 1947 (Box DG/6)
    - London, 1944 (Box DG/6)
    - Director General - Memoranda, etc. (Box DG/6)
    - Director General - Miscellaneous (Box DG/6)
    - Director General - Missions, Visit to, July 1945 (Box DG/6)
    - Director General - Office (Box DG/6)
    - Director General - Speech Material (Box DG/6)
    - Director General - Speeches (Box DG/6)
    - Displaced Persons (Box DG/7)
    - 1944 (Box DG/7)
    - through 31 March 1947 (Box DG/7)
    - 1 April - 15 June 1947 (Box DG/7)
    - 15 June 1947 - March 1948 (Box DG/7)
    - Displaced Persons Division - Miscellaneous (Box DG/7)
    - Distribution, Observation of (Box DG/7)
    - Distribution of UNRRA Supplies (Box DG/7)
    - Divisions Transferred from the Secretariat - Historian's Office and Translation Division (Box DG/7)
    - Down-grading (Box DG/7)
    - Economic Adviser (Box DG/7)
    - Economic and Social Security (Box DG/7)
    - Economic Recovery in the Countries Assisted by UNRRA (H.I.A.S.ter copy) (Box DG/7)
    - Economic Studies: Inflation & Relief (Box DG/7)
    - Education (Box DG/7)
    - Educational Rehabilitation (Box DG/7)
    - Education, UNRRA Contracts on (Box DG/7)
    - Emergency Aid to Paying Governments (Box DG/7)
    - Employment Record, Headquarters (Box DG/7)
    - European Inland Transport Organization (EITO) (Box DG/7)
    - Ex-Enemy Countries (Box DG/7)
    - FCC - FB15, Reports (Box DG/7)
    - Far Eastern Foundation (Box DG/7)
    - Fats and Oils, Argentina to Russia (Box DG/7)
    - Film (Box DG/7)
    - Finance (Box DG/7)
    - Finance & Accounts, Bureau of - Miscellaneous (Box DG/7)
    - Finance & Administration, Bureau of (folders 1-6) (Box DG/7)
    - Finance & Administration (Box DG/8)
    - Miscellaneous (Box DG/8)
    - 1943-44 (Box DG/8)
    - Treasurer, January - April 1944 (Box DG/8)
    - May - July 1944 (Box DG/8)
    - August - October 1944 (Box DG/8)
    - Financial Adviser (W. Sokolowski) (Box DG/8)
    - Financial and Economic Reporting (Box DG/8)
    - Financial Instructions to Chief of Missions (Box DG/8)
    - Food Supplies (Box DG/8)
    - Food and Agriculture, Interim Commission on (Box DG/8)
    - Food and Agriculture Organization (Box DG/8)
    - Food and Agriculture Organization (Weisl) (Box DG/8)
    - Food and Agriculture Organization of the UN (Box DG/8)
    - Foreign Economic Administration (Box DG/8)
    - Crowley, Lee (Box DG/8)
    - FEA - UNRRA Relationships (Box DG/8)
    - Funds (Box DG/8)
    - Commitment (Box DG/8)
    - Provision of Lire to Trieste (Box DG/8)
    - Residual (Box DG/8)
    - Special Report on Status of UNRRA Dollar Funds, Headquarters, as of May 1944 (Box DG/8)
    - General Counsel (Box DG/8)
    - General Counsel, Office of, 1946-1948 (Box DG/8)
    - General Letters (Box DG/8)
    - Governmental Agencies (Box DG/8)
    - Grain (Box DG/8)
    - Grain, 1 (Box DG/8)
    - Grain, 2-1 April 1946 - February 1947 (Box DG/8)
    - Grain Collection and AH.I.A.S.sment (Box DG/8)
    - Grain, 4 (Box DG/8)
    - Cables on AH.I.A.S.sment and Grain Distribution (Box DG/8)
    - "H" (Box DG/8)
    - Handbook, Headquarters Rundown Handbook, UNRRA Travel Health Division (Box DG/8)
    - Health Division (Box DG/8)
    - Dec. 1943 - January 1944 (Box DG/8)
    - Feb. - October 1944 (Box DG/8)
    - General (Box DG/8)
    - Hendrickson, Roy (Box DG/8)
    - Middle East Trip (Box DG/8)
    - Miscellaneous file (Box DG/8)
    - History of UNRRA (Box DG/8)
    - History of UNRRA (Box DG/9)
    - Hoehler, Fred - Alphabetical (Box DG/9)
    - Immunities Bill, Legal Division, General Counsel (Box DG/9)
    - Industrial Rehabilitation Division, Bureau of Supply, Administration (Box DG/9)
    - Industrial Rehabilitation (Box DG/9)
    - International Children's Fund (Box DG/9)
    - International Emergency Food Committee (I.E.F.C.) (Box DG/9)
    - International Emergency Food Council, 2nd meeting, 14 October 1946 (Box DG/9)
    - International Emergence Food Fund, Replies to Appeal for Public Support (Box DG/9)
    - International Labor Organization (Box DG/9)
    - International Refugee Organization (IRQ) (Box DG/9)
    - International Sanitary Convention, Health Division (Box DG/9)
    - Interrelations (Box DG/9)
    - FEA (Foreign Economic Administration) - UNRRA (Box DG/9)
    - General (Box DG/9)
    - Military - UNRRA (Box DG/9)
    - "J" (Box DG/9)
    - Jackson, Hugh (Box DG/9)
    - Jackson Papers (Box DG/9)
    - 5. 27 November - 25 April 1944 (Box DG/9)
    - 6. Early Records Concerning UNRRA Relations, 2 June 1943 -11 January 1944, plus 1 letter 20 October 1944 (Box DG/9)
    - 8. UNRRA Relations with the Military (Box DG/9)
    - 13. 1st Council Session (Box DG/9)
    - 14. Supplies, Combined Boards, Miscellaneous (Box DG/9)
    - 15. Confidential Letters from Jackson to Leith-Ross (Box DG/9)
    - 17. France, 27 May 1944 - 29 January 1945 (Box DG/9)
    - 18. UNRRA and the Balkan (Box DG/9)
    - 19. Poland (Box DG/9)
    - 20. Russia, 22 May 1944 - 14 October 1944 (Box DG/9)
    - 21. Yugoslavia, 16 June - 20 December 1944 (Box DG/9)
    - 22. Administrative Organization, Headquarters and ERO, 16 February 1944- 1 May 1945 (Box DG/9)
    - 23. Emergency Relief, 1 January - 17 February 1945 (Box DG/9)
    - 24. Confidential Letters, Jackson to Mooney, January - February 1945 (Box DG/9)
    - 25. Confidential Letters, Jackson to the Director General, February - April 1945 (Box DG/9)
    - 26. Miscellaneous (Box DG/9)
    - 27. Extra Copies (Box DG/9)
    - Jackson, Robert G.A. (Commander) - Miscellaneous (Box DG/9)
    - "K" (Box DG/9)
    - "L" (Box DG/9)
    - Lacy, William S. - Miscellaneous (Box DG/9)
    - La Guardia - Miscellaneous (Box DG/9)
    - League of Nations (Box DG/9)
    - Leave Policy (Box DG/9)
    - Leave (Sick) Provisions (Box DG/9)
    - Lehman, Herbert, January - July 1945 (Box DG/9)
    - Liaison Officers (Box DG/9)
    - Library (Box DG/9)
    - Library, Transfer to UN, Final Report (Box DG/9)
    - Liquidation (Box DG/9)
    - Liquidation (2 folders) (Box DG/9)
    - Liquidation of UNRRA Library (Box DG/9)
    - Liquidation Paper, Central Committee (Box DG/9)
    - UNRRA, Central Liquidation Plans for (Box DG/9)
    - Livestock (Box DG/9)
    - Losses, Transit (Box DG/9)
    - "Mc" (Box DG/9)
    - Mail (Box DG/9)
    - Malaria Control (Box DG/9)
    - Manual, Field Reporting (Box DG/9)
    - Manual, Operations Covering the Storage and Transportation of UNRRA Supplies in Areas of Relief Operations (Box DG/10)
    - Meetings (Box DG/10)
    - Director General (Box DG/10)
    - Notes, Miscellaneous, between Director General and Officials of Various Member Governments (Box DG/10)
    - Notes of Meetings (including staff meetings), March 1944 - April 1946 (Box DG/10)
    - Notes of Meetings, Reading file (Box DG/10)
    - Staff Meetings (Box DG/10)
    - Staff Meetings (Box DG/10)
    - Military, Relations with (Box DG/10)
    - Minesweepers (Box DG/10)
    - Miscellaneous (Box DG/10)
    - National Catholic Welfare Supplies (Box DG/10)
    - Neutrals (Box DG/10)
    - Neutrals, UNRRA Relations with (Box DG/10)
    - "0" (Box DG/10)
    - Office of Country Mission Affairs (Box DG/10)
    - Office of the Far East (Box DG/10)
    - Organization (Box DG/10)
    - Operations Responsibility, Correspondence (Box DG/10)
    - Organizational Memoranda (?) Developed in the ERO (Box DG/10)
    - Outplacement (Box DG/10)
    - Personal - Casualties (Box DG/10)
    - Personnel Division (Box DG/10)
    - General (Box DG/10)
    - Training (Box DG/10)
    - Personnel (Box DG/10)
    - Miscellaneous (Box DG/10)
    - Missions (Box DG/10)
    - Policy (Box DG/10)
    - Regulations for Field Service (Box DG/10)
    - Status of (Box DG/10)
    - Suggested (Box DG/10)
    - Washington (Box DG/10)
    - POL, General (Box DG/10)
    - Policy on Refugees (Box DG/10)
    - Policy on Refugees (Box DG/11)
    - Policy for Transfer of Shipping Responsibilities (A. Katzin) (Box DG/11)
    - Principal Action 11 March - 10 April 1944 for Gov. Lehman, Papers Relating to (Box DG/11)
    - Privileges and Immunities (Box DG/11)
    - Procedure, Cable (Box DG/11)
    - Proceeds of Sale (Box DG/11)
    - Procurement (Box DG/11)
    - Procurement, Food (Box DG/11)
    - Program, Child Feeding (Box DG/11)
    - Reports, Loading and Shipment (Box DG/11)
    - Salary (Box DG/11)
    - Policy regarding Russians (Box DG/11)
    - Scales Policy (Box DG/11)
    - Severance Pay (Box DG/11)
    - Salter, Sir Arthur (Box DG/11)
    - Sayre, Francis B. (Box DG/11)
    - Secretariat (Box DG/11)
    - Secretariat (Box DG/11)
    - Commendations to (Box DG/11)
    - Liquidation (Box DG/11)
    - Memos to Staff (Box DG/11)
    - Organization (Box DG/12)
    - Organization and Functions (Box DG/12)
    - Residual Functions (Box DG/12)
    - Security (Box DG/12)
    - Seeds (Box DG/12)
    - Services, Bureau of (Box DG/12)
    - Shipping (Box DG/12)
    - Shipping (Box DG/12)
    - Anticipated Monthly Tonnage (Box DG/12)
    - General (Box DG/12)
    - Shipping Operations, Status of (Box DG/12)
    - Shipping Policy (Box DG/12)
    - Shortages and Losses (Box DG/12)
    - SLAO (Supplies to Liberated and Conquered Areas, Official Committee) (Box DG/12)
    - Space (Box DG/12)
    - Special Committee Investigating the National Defense Program: Executive Session with UNRRA on Overseas Surplus Property (Box DG/12)
    - Specialists, Policy on Appointment of (Box DG/12)
    - Speech by Mr. Sayre before Toledo Committee for the Organization of Peace, 5 March 1944. (Box DG/12)
    - State Department (Box DG/12)
    - Letters from Lehman to, 1943 (Box DG/12)
    - Letters from Lehman to, 1944 (Box DG/12)
    - Letters from Cordell Hull, 1944 (Box DG/12)
    - Supplies (Box DG/12)
    - Administrative (Box DG/12)
    - Agriculture (Box DG/12)
    - Agrehab Program (closed) (Box DG/12)
    - Bureau of Supply (Box DG/12)
    - Bureau of Supply, Hendrickson (Box DG/12)
    - January - July 1944 (Box DG/12)
    - August 1944 (Box DG/12)
    - Miscellaneous (Box DG/12)
    - Miscellaneous (Box DG/12)
    - Procurement Policy (Box DG/12)
    - Supplies for Displaced Persons in China (Box DG/12)
    - PX (Box DG/12)
    - Surplus (Box DG/12)
    - Surplus Administrative Property (Box DG/12)
    - Taxation (Box DG/12)
    - Telephone Calls (Box DG/12)
    - Telephone Calls, Transatlantic (Box DG/12)
    - Telephone Conservation Notes (Box DG/12)
    - Training (Box DG/12)
    - Training Program (Box DG/13)
    - Training Program (Box DG/13)
    - Chinese Technical Experts (Box DG/13)
    - Nurses (Box DG/13)
    - Personnel (Box DG/13)
    - Trans-blockade (Box DG/13)
    - Transport (Box DG/13)
    - Transport, Inland, General Correspondence (Box DG/13)
    - Transportation Charges (Box DG/13)
    - Transportation Charges (Box DG/13)
    - Travel (Box DG/13)
    - UNESCO (Box DG/13)
    - Uniforms (Box DG/13)
    - United National Clothing Collection, A Report to the President of the U.S (Box DG/13)
    - United Nations, Material for the General Assembly of (Box DG/13)
    - United Nations Organizations (Box DG/13)
    - UNRRA (Box DG/13)
    - November - December 1943 (Box DG/13)
    - Organization of (3 folders) (Box DG/13)
    - Transfer of UNRRA to International Agencies (Box DG/13)
    - UNRRA Staff Society (Box DG/13)
    - UNRRA - UN Joint Planning I, to 27 April 1947 (Box DG/13)
    - UNRRA - UN Joint Planning II, 1 May 1947 - January 1948 (Box DG/13)
    - UNRRA - UN Joint Planning Commission, Minutes (Box DG/13)
    - UNRRA - UN Working Party (2 folders) (Box DG/13)
    - UNRRA Dead File, U-l, 5/11/46 (Box DG/13)
    - Voluntary Agencies (Box DG/13)
    - "W" (Box DG/13)
    - Wagons, Railway (Box DG/13)
    - War Department, Alphabetical, Hildring, John H. (Box DG/13)
    - Watercraft, China (Box DG/13)
    - Welfare (Box DG/13)
    - Welfare Branch (Box DG/13)
    - Welfare Division - General (Box DG/13)
    - Wind-up of UNRRA #1 (Box DG/13)
    - Wind-up of UNRRA #2 (Box DG/13)
    - World Health Organization (WHO), Transfer of Supervisory Functions to (Box DG/13)
    - Young-Sinclair (Box DG/13)
  - Subseries III.2: Country File
    - Albania (Box DG/14)
    - April - December 1946, 1 (Box DG/14)
    - January 1947 - March 1948, 2 (Box DG/14)
    - Special (closed) (Box DG/14)
    - Algeria (Box DG/14)
    - Australia, Locomotives for China (Box DG/14)
    - Australia - New Zealand Mission (Box DG/14)
    - Nugent - Lehman and Miscellaneous Matters (Box DG/14)
    - Reports on Missions by Lithgow Osborne Austria (Box DG/14)
    - February - December 1946 (closed), 1 (Box DG/14)
    - January - September 1947, 2 (Box DG/14)
    - Balkans - Cairo Office (Box DG/14)
    - AML Agreement (Allied Military Lira) (Box DG/14)
    - Administration, 1 January - 31 May 1944 (Box DG/14)
    - Administration, 1 June - 31 July 1944 (Box DG/14)
    - Administration, 1 August - 30 September 1944 (Box DG/14)
    - Administration, Miscellaneous, October 1944 - March 1945 (Box DG/14)
    - Reports - General (Box DG/14)
    - Reports - Laird Archer (Box DG/14)
    - Reports - Matthews, December 1944 (Box DG/14)
    - elegrams from, 1944, #400- (Box DG/14)
    - Telegrams to, 1944, #416-886 (Box DG/14)
    - Balkan Mission (Box DG/14)
    - Administrative Plans and Budget Requirements (Box DG/14)
    - Cairo Office Supplies (Box DG/14)
    - Cairo Office, Middle East Supply Center (Box DG/14)
    - Balkan Supply Center (Box DG/14)
    - Belgium (Box DG/14)
    - Bolivia (Box DG/14)
    - Brazil (Box DG/14)
    - Brazilian Office, Closure (Box DG/14)
    - Bulgaria (Box DG/14)
    - Burma (Box DG/14)
    - Byelorussian Soviet Socialist Republic (Box DG/14)
    - Canada (Box DG/14)
    - Chile (Box DG/14)
    - China (Box DG/14)
    - Closure (Box DG/14)
    - Miscellaneous, 1944 (Box DG/14)
    - 1944 (Box DG/14)
    - 1945 (Box DG/14)
    - January - April 1946 (Box DG/14)
    - April - July 1946 (Box DG/15)
    - 14 August 1946 - 30 March 1947 (Box DG/15)
    - 1 April - 16 June 1947 (Box DG/15)
    - 15 June - 25 July 1947 (Box DG/15)
    - 26 July - 1 September 1947 (Box DG/15)
    - I September 1947 - 10 October 1947 (Box DG/15)
    - II October 1947 - April 1948 (Box DG/15)
    - Distribution in Communist Areas (Box DG/15)
    - Hongkong Finances (Box DG/15)
    - Cotton Program (Box DG/15)
    - Personnel (Box DG/15)
    - #37, April 6, re: Staley-Dawson Arrival in Chunking (Box DG/15)
    - Requirements (Box DG/15)
    - Botra Trusteeship, July 1947 - September 1948 (Box DG/15)
    - China and the Far East - General (Box DG/15)
    - Medical Relief and Rehabilitation Problems (Box DG/15)
    - UNRRA in China (Box DG/15)
    - Colombia (Box DG/15)
    - Costa Rica (Box DG/15)
    - Cuba (Box DG/15)
    - Czechoslovakia (3 folders) plus: (Box DG/15)
    - 4. 15 March - 31 October 1946 (closed) (Box DG/15)
    - 2. 1 November 1946 - 28 February 1947 (closed) (Box DG/15)
    - 3. November 1946 - April 1948 (Box DG/15)
    - P.O.L. (Box DG/15)
    - Shipping Charges and Operations (Box DG/16)
    - Dr. Frank Hunk's Report on the Economic and Financial Situation (Box DG/16)
    - Denmark (Box DG/16)
    - Dodecanese Islands (Box DG/16)
    - Dominican Republic (Box DG/16)
    - Ecuador (Box DG/16)
    - Egypt (Box DG/16)
    - El Salvador (Box DG/16)
    - El Shatt (Box DG/16)
    - Ethiopia (3 folders) plus: (Box DG/16)
    - Agreement with United Kingdom (Box DG/16)
    - U.S. Technical Project (Box DG/16)
    - European Regional Office (Box DG/16)
    - Europe - Surprop (surplus property (Box DG/16)
    - European Regional Office (ERO) (Box DG/16)
    - Administration, 6 November 1944 - 24 February 1945 (Box DG/16)
    - Accounting Conference (Box DG/16)
    - Areas Coordination Committee of France (Box DG/16)
    - Bureau of Services, Areas, Missions, Organization, Functions, Budget, etc. (Box DG/16)
    - General Correspondence (Box DG/16)
    - London, Distribution of Responsibility between London and Headquarters (Box DG/16)
    - Correspondence and Notes, Confidential (Box DG/16)
    - Memoranda (Box DG/16)
    - London Regional Office 1944 (Box DG/16)
    - Meeting, Regional Divisions (Box DG/16)
    - London, Miscellaneous (Box DG/16)
    - Minutes, Staff Meeting #364-501, 1 October 1946 - 27 June 1947 (Box DG/16)
    - Minutes, Staff Meeting #502-598, 1 July 1947 - 11 May 1948 (Box DG/16)
    - Miscellaneous, 1944-45 (Box DG/16)
    - Miscellaneous, January - November 1946 (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - Miscellaneous, November 1946 - 30 April 1947 (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - Miscellaneous (4), 1 May 1947 - April 1948 (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - Organization (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - Organization, Procedures, etc., London Office (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - Personnel (General), London (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - Report to Director General Europe (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - Survey of Information from London (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - Survey of Information from London, Report of (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - Telephone Calls, Weekly, with London - Contents (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - Telephone Communications, ERO Headquarters, 1945 (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - Telephone Conversations, 1944-46 (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - Far East (2 folders) (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - Finland (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - France (2 folders) (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - French Mission (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - France, Director General's Discussions in - Supplies to Sinistres (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - French Committee of National Liberation (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - Germany (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - German, G-1 (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - German Mission, Displaced Persons (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - Greece (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - Food Stuffs (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)
    - DDT (Box DG/17, Folder Side 1)